xcelenergy.com 2014-10-24

# Xcel Energy Privacy Policy

                                                                                    en Espanol
                           Xcel Energy Privacy Policy
Overview
Xcel Energy Inc., its wholly owned affiliates and subsidiaries (collectively, “Xcel Energy”)
understands that privacy is important to you, and we respect your privacy concerns. This
Privacy Policy describes our privacy practices.
The Policy explains:
      What information we collect from and about you when you use our products and
       services, communicate with us, visit our websites, or interact with us through social
       media
      How we use and share the information we collect
      The choices we offer you regarding how we use and disclose information about you,
       and how to exercise those choices
      How you can access and request that we correct the information we maintain about
       you
      How we safeguard the information we maintain, and
      How you can ask questions about our privacy practices and seek resolution of any
       concerns you may have regarding our handling of your information
Information We Collect
We may obtain information about you through various sources, such as:
      Phone, fax, e-mail, social media and other means by which you communicate with us
      A utility meter we have installed at your home or business
      Xcel Energy websites, social media pages, mobile applications and other interactive
       assets that you access
      Surveys, contests, sweepstakes and other promotions
      Our parent, affiliate or subsidiary companies
      Our service providers and other third parties
The types of information we may obtain about you include:
      Contact information (such as name, postal address, e-mail address, phone number)
      Demographic data (such as date of birth, home ownership status and household
       income)
      Details about your home (such as dwelling age, size and type, and details about
       appliances and other energy-related equipment used in the home)
      Customer service addresses and dates of service
      Information about your participation in our renewable energy, energy efficiency, or
       energy conservation programs

        Account history with Xcel Energy (such as disconnection notices issued,
         disconnection and reconnection dates, payment arrangement dates, late payment
         notices, and applied late fees)
        Account notes detailing our interactions with you via phone, e-mail, fax, and/or social
         media
        User name or ID and password for an account you may establish on our websites
        Energy Usage Data specific to your account (the type of Energy Usage Data collected
         from utility meters and the frequency with which we collect that information varies
         depending on the type of meter installed; our website provides more information
         about our metering technology)
        Customer payment history and details, including: payment amounts and dates,
         financial account number, routing number, and billing address
        Credit report information
        Your Social Security Number
             o We ask for and use SSNs when setting up new service to confirm the
                 customer’s identity
             o We also use SSNs to protect against fraud by confirming that we are speaking
                 to the customer of record before providing account access or taking action on
                 the account, and to aid our ability to collect on past-due debts.
             o In Colorado, Texas, and New Mexico, with your permission, we may also use
                 your SSN to obtain a credit indicator from a consumer reporting agency to
                 help us determine whether a deposit will be required before we establish the
                 residential service you request. We do not obtain full credit reports or credit
                 scores from consumer reporting agencies when establishing residential
                 service.
        Other information you may provide to us
Web Browsing Details
When you visit our websites or social media pages we may collect certain information by
automated means, such as cookies and web beacons. A “cookie” is a text file that a websites
sends to a visitor’s computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify the
visitor’s browser or to store information or settings in the browser. A “web beacon,” also
known as an Internet tag, pixel tag or clear GIF, is used to transmit information back to a web
server. We also may use website analytics tools that collect information about visitor traffic
on our websites or social media pages. Examples of the information we may collect by
automated means include details about the devices our visitors use to access the Internet
(such as the Internet service provider, IP address and device, browser and operating system
type); URLs that refer visitors to our websites; dates, times, and lengths of visits to our
websites; site navigation patterns; a general geographic location from which a visitor
accesses our websites; and search terms that visitors use to reach our websites.
How We Use the Information We Collect
We may use the information we obtain about you to:
        Assist you in establishing your account with Xcel Energy

        Provide, bill and collect for Xcel Energy products and services
        Communicate with you, respond to your questions and comments, and provide
         customer support
        Provide you access to your information via the My Account site
        Administer your participation in events, programs, surveys, and other offers and
         promotions
        Operate, evaluate and improve our business and the regulated products and services
         we offer (including developing new products and services, analyzing our products
         and services, optimizing customer experience on websites, managing our energy
         distribution system and our communications, reducing costs and improving service
         accuracy and reliability, and performing accounting, auditing and other internal
         functions)
        Create aggregated or de-identified energy usage data
        Protect against and prevent fraud, unauthorized transactions, claims and other
         liabilities, including past due accounts
        Manage risk exposure
        Comply with applicable legal and regulatory requirements
Online Advertising
You may see ads about our products and services on other websites because we participate in
advertising networks. Ad networks allow us to target our advertising to users through
demographic, behavioral and contextual means. These networks track your online activities
over time by collecting information through automated means, including through the use of
cookies, web server logs, web beacons and other methods. The ad network vendors may
collect information about your visits to websites that participate in the vendors’ advertising
networks, such as the pages or advertisements you have viewed, and the actions you take on
the sites. The networks use this information to show you advertisements for our products and
services. This data collection and ad targeting take place both on our websites and on third-
party websites that participate in the ad networks. This process also helps us track the
effectiveness of our marketing efforts.
Information Disclosures
Overview
We do not disclose information about you except as described in this Privacy Policy. This
means that, with the exception of disclosures of the information described in this Policy and
any disclosures you or your authorized agent have specifically authorized, you can expect
that we will keep the information that we maintain about you private or confidential, and not
otherwise disclose it.
As we explain in the next section, certain disclosures of information about you do not require
your consent because they are specifically permitted or required by applicable laws and
regulations. Other disclosures will only occur after we obtain your explicit authorization.
Nothing in this Privacy Policy precludes you from directly sharing your own information
with a third party that may or may not be affiliated with Xcel Energy. In such circumstances,

Xcel Energy is not responsible for unauthorized disclosure or use of that information by the
third party to which you disclose your information.
Information Disclosures for Which Authorization Is Not Required
We may disclose information about you as required or permitted by law or applicable
regulations, including to a federal, state or local governmental agency with the power to
compel such disclosure, or in response to a subpoena or court order.
We may disclose information about you to service providers who perform services on our
behalf, such as companies that assist us in providing products and services to customers,
billing customers, or processing credit card payments. We prohibit these service providers
from using or disclosing the information we provide them, except as necessary to perform
specific services on our behalf or to comply with legal requirements.
Except for the instances listed in this section, we will not disclose to third parties your Social
Security Number, banking or credit card information, driver license number, credit reporting
information, bankruptcy or probate information.
We may disclose aggregated or de-identified energy usage data to third parties. We aggregate
and/or anonymize the information in accordance with applicable legal and regulatory
requirements, including those designed to prevent the re-identification of the information.
We also reserve the right to disclose information about you in connection with: (1) referral of
past due accounts for collection or sale of such accounts; or (2) a transfer of service rights to
another utility provider (which would generally be subject to your state Public Utility or
Public Service Commission review and approval). Should such a sale, merger or transfer
occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the recipient to use information you have
provided to us in a manner that is consistent with our Privacy Policy. Following such a sale,
merger or transfer, you may contact the entity to which we transferred your information with
any inquiries concerning the processing of that information.
Information Disclosures that Require Customer Authorization
We may share certain information about you with a third party if you have previously
authorized the disclosure in writing, including:
        Energy Usage Data – The following links provide access to our Energy Usage Data
         release authorization forms:
             o Colorado Customers - Electric Energy Usage Data Release Form
             o Colorado Customers - Natural Gas or Steam Energy Usage Data Release
             o Customers in Michigan, Minnesota, New Mexico, North Dakota, South
                 Dakota, Texas and Wisconsin – Electric and Natural Gas Energy Usage Data
                 Release Form
        Requests for disclosure of customer information other than Energy Usage Data:
             o Service Verification Letters
             o Credit Reference Letters

             o Lock Authorization Forms
             o Custom Letters – for example, written verification of start/stop orders,
                 disconnection dates, explanation of a payment arrangement, confirmation that
                 the account is current, recap of a phone call, etc. Custom letters typically
                 include the customer’s name, account number, service address, and alternate
                 mailing address (when applicable)
             o The following link provides access to our One-Time Release of Information
                 (other than Customer Energy Usage Data)
Prior to authorizing the disclosure of your information to a third party, you should consider
the third party’s proposed scope, purpose, and use of the information – including whether
they can use it for other purposes that may extend beyond the purpose for which you initially
authorized its disclosure.
With respect to disclosures of Customer Energy Usage Data, please note that, depending on
the type of metering equipment and supporting infrastructure, it may be possible to obtain
insight into activities within your home or business through analysis of Energy Usage Data.
If you decline a request from a third party to authorize access to your Energy Usage Data,
that decision will not affect the provision of any service you receive from Xcel Energy.
Information Disclosures to HomeSmart
With your consent, we will release information required for participation in a HomeSmart
from Xcel Energy® appliance maintenance program to our non-regulated affiliates that
operate those programs. The following links provide access to the disclosure authorization
forms for the HomeSmart Minnesota and HomeSmart Colorado programs:
             o Customer Information Disclosure Authorization – HomeSmart Minnesota
             o Data Privacy Consent form -- HomeSmart Colorado
Our HomeSmart affiliates have their own privacy policies that specifically govern the
information that they collect about you. To review these policies, when you visit a
HomeSmart website, please click on the site’s link to their privacy policy.
Revoking Consent
You may at any time terminate or limit any consent previously provided that authorizes a
third party or HomeSmart from Xcel Energy® to access or use your information by sending a
request to us via e-mail (datarequest@xcelenergy.com), fax (1-866-208-8732), or mail (P.O.
Box 8, Eau Claire, Wisconsin 54702).
Your Choices
You have certain choices about what information we collect from you and how we
communicate with you:

Marketing E-mails
You may choose not to receive marketing e-mail communications from us by clicking on the
“unsubscribe” link in a marketing e-mail we send to you. We will discontinue this type of
contact with you within ten days after we receive your ‘unsubscribe’ request. Please note that
even if you opt out of our marketing e-mail communications, you will continue to receive
non-marketing e-mails related to your account transactions.
Cookies
Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you
receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. Please note, however, that without
cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of our websites’ features.
Online Advertising
To opt out of receiving marketing communications through the advertising networks of our
ad network vendors, please click the “Online Advertising Opt-Out” link, then click “Select
all” on the linked site, and then press the “Submit” button.
Access and Correction
You may request to confirm the information we maintain about you in the ordinary course of
business, and request us to make an update or correction of inaccuracies in that information,
free of charge via our My Account site or by contacting us as specified in the How to Contact
Us section at the end of this Privacy Policy. In some cases we may deny your request for
information. If we deny your request for access to information we maintain about you, we
will notify you of our reason for the denial.
Links to Other Websites
Our websites may contain links to other sites for your convenience and information. These
sites may be operated by companies not affiliated with Xcel Energy. Linked sites may have
their own privacy policies or notices, which you should review if you visit those websites.
We are not responsible for the content of any websites not affiliated with Xcel Energy, any
use of those sites, or those sites’ privacy practices.
How We Protect Your Information
We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the
privacy and security of the information we maintain about you. Please note that no electronic
transmission of information can be entirely secure. We cannot guarantee that the security
measures we have in place to safeguard information will never fail, or that those measures
will always be sufficient or effective.
To help protect yourself, we recommend that you protect the confidentiality of any user name

or ID and password you use to access any online services, including those provided by Xcel
Energy. You are responsible for all activity on the website accessed using your user name or
ID and password. You should also sign off your accounts and close your browser window
when you have finished your visit to our websites. We will never ask for your Xcel Energy
My Account site password via e-mail or phone.
Our website includes tips about steps you can take to help Protect Your Information,
including identifying potential scams and securing information you may access online about
your Xcel Energy account.
Children’s Privacy
Our websites are general audience websites; we do not intend or knowingly use them to
collect any personal information from children younger than the age of thirteen (13). If we
discover that we have collected personal information from an individual younger than the age
of thirteen (13), we will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete that personal
information. If you are the parent or legal guardian of a child younger than age 13 and
believe that Xcel Energy has collected personal information from your child, please contact
us as indicated in the “Contact Us” section of this policy.
Updates to Our Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect
changes in our information practices. Please regularly review the content of this Privacy
Policy. We will post a prominent notice on our websites to notify you of material changes to
our Privacy Policy. We also have indicated at the bottom of the Policy when it was most
recently updated. Amendments to this Privacy Policy will become effective when posted on
our websites. Your continued use of our websites, products and services provided by Xcel
Energy after such posting will be deemed your acceptance of any changes to our Privacy
Policy.
How to Contact Us
For more information regarding our privacy practices, if you have any questions or comments
about this Privacy Policy, or if you would like us to update information we have about you or
your preferences, please contact us by e-mail at inquire@xcelenergy.com, or call 1-800-895-
4999.
Effective Date: January 10, 2014
History of Revisions: August 3, 2012
